<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SÖREN SCHNEIDER</title><link>https://www.soerenschneider.com/</link><description>Recent content on SÖREN SCHNEIDER</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 14:44:35 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.soerenschneider.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PROJECTS</title><link>https://www.soerenschneider.com/projects/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 09:37:50 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.soerenschneider.com/projects/</guid><description>PROJECTS @ HOME The Time I Accidentally Built My Own &amp;ldquo;Cloud&amp;rdquo; Platform During the pandemic I leveraged the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m having deployed hardware on three different, geo-distributed regions so I semi-consciounsly built my own highly-available, on-premise &amp;ldquo;Cloud&amp;rdquo; platform.
I used existing software components I already have knowledge in and additionally wrote some software myself. Basic building blocks, such as blob storage, databases, service discovery and Kubernetes nodes are highly-available through (almost) immutable VMs based on a terraformed libvirt API.</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://www.soerenschneider.com/cv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 14:44:35 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.soerenschneider.com/cv/</guid><description>ABSTRACT 10+ years of working experience in the industry Started out as Software-Engineer and later Software-Architect, working more closely to Cloud Infrastructures for the last 5+ years Generally interested in Software Resilience, Distributed Systems and IT Security Knowledge (different levels) in AWS, Azure &amp;amp; Google Cloud Platform Writing software preferably in Golang and Python Currently getting deeper into Azure and trying to tackle the steep learning curve of Rust&amp;rsquo;s lifetimes SENIOR CLOUD ENGINEER @ SAP FIONEER (Remote), 12/2021 &amp;ndash; NOW CORE OBJECTIVES Help shaping and implementing the MVP of SAP Fioneer&amp;rsquo;s Commercial Lending product TASKS Involved in building the company&amp;rsquo;s upcoming Azure architecture Realized secrets management based on Azure Key Vault, GitHub Actions and Terraform TECHNOLOGIES Golang, Python Azure Kubernetes w.</description></item><item><title>ABOUT ME</title><link>https://www.soerenschneider.com/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 19:58:44 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.soerenschneider.com/about/</guid><description>Hi! After living in Köln for almost ten years, I recently moved further up the Rhine to Düsseldorf. I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a Senior Cloud Engineer, but I&amp;rsquo;m kind of a jack of all trades, having worked in several similar positions and generally being interested in various technical topics.
I also like to invest a good portion of my spare time on technology: coding, reading technical books, running (semi-)professional home labs, trying to keep up with new technologies or paradigms – or short: practicing continuous improvement.</description></item></channel></rss>